The most wonderful entertainment in the whole wide wonderful world!
A Hole in the Head is a comedy, drama film directed by Frank Capra.
An impractical widower tries to hang onto his
Miami hotel and his 12-year-old son.
Tony Manetta, played by Frank Sinatra.
Mario Manetta, played by Edward G. Robinson.
Eloise Rogers, played by Eleanor Parker.
Sophie Manetta, played by Thelma Ritter.
Shirl, played by Carolyn Jones.
Jerry Marks, played by Keenan Wynn.
A Hole in the Head is a 1959 DeLuxe Color CinemaScope American comedy film
directed by Frank Capra and starring Frank Sinatra, Edward G.
Robinson, Eleanor Parker, Keenan Wynn, Carolyn Jones and
Thelma Ritter and released by United Artists.
It was based upon the play of the same name by Arnold Schulman.
The film introduced the Academy Award-winning song "High Hopes" by Sammy Cahn and
Jimmy Van Heusen, a Sinatra standard used as a campaign song by John F.
Kennedy during the presidential election the following year.
Sinatra sings "All My Tomorrows," another Cahn/Van
Heusen song, under the opening titles.
The film explores themes of miami, florida, widower, single
father, greyhound racing, father son relationship.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.